Nitin Agrawal

<u>linkedin.com/in/nitinagrawalink</u> Portfolio: Visit my website

OBJECTIVE

ecnitin13@gmail.com

I am a Product Manager with 7+ years of product experience in an edtech organization. I specialize in leading product development and strategy, driving a 30% increase in user engagement and revenue growth. My experience has predominantly revolved around enhancing and expanding B2B product offerings, with a particular focus on driving substantial growth in both user engagement and revenue. Additionally, I have played a pivotal role in shaping the B2C aspects during the initial stages. Excited to grow, learn and make a meaningful impact.

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration in Entrepreneurship from Amity University (Noida)

Bachelor of Electronics & Communications, Uttar Pradesh Technical University

2020 - 2022

2010 - 2014

KEY SKILLS

• Product Roadmap • Prioritization • Resource Planning • Wireframe & Prototyping • Product Strategy • Competitive Analysis • Market Analysis • User Research • User Experience • User Thinking • Data Analytics • Root Cause Analysis • Agile Methodologies • SQL • Product Backlog • Scrum • Task Allocation • User Stories • User Centric Design • SAAS • Problem Solving • Strategic Thinking • Product Launch • User Acceptance Testing

Tools

• Jira • Power BI • Balsamiq • Hotjar • Figma • Notion • Google Analytics

EXPERIENCE

Product Manager Apr 2021 - Current

Eduspace Technologies Pvt. Ltd. (Proctur) Pune, India

• Led a 7-member agile product team and 16-member of engineering team, to deliver successful products from concept to execution.

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to create 2 web portals and 2 mobile applications.
- Developed a school/coaching ERP solution and led its implementation, resulting in over **1,000+ users** adopting the system for improved operational efficiency.
- Launched a freemium app, achieving 3,000+ downloads within 2 months and a 20% sales boost in 30 days.
- Drove a 70% platform growth by defining user flows, wireframes, and an overall product strategy for products.
- Authored user stories and contributed to UX design, resulting in a 40% increase in new customer acquisition.
- Increased app visit-to-sale conversion rate by 75% and a complete app redesign, focusing on supporting educational administrators.
- Streamlined financial operations by integrating multiple payment gateways with ERP portal (Razorpay, PayPal & PayTabs).
- Managed backlog, prioritized features, and planned team tasks, leading to improved project delivery timelines and team productivity.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams (BA, UX/UI Designers, Tech, QA, Sales, Support, and Marketing) to enhance product development and align strategies, resulting in improved team coordination and product quality

Associate Product Manager

Apr 2019 - Mar 2021

Eduspace Technologies Pvt. Ltd. (Proctur) Pune, India

- Utilized user data to address technical issues, resulting in a **40-50% improvement in user satisfaction** through bug fixes and interface enhancements.
- Coordinated cross-departmental communication, arranging bi-weekly all-hands meetings for team alignment.
- Analyzed project scope through competition assessment, customer interviews, and feature request reviews, leading to more informed product development decisions.
- Collaborated closely with the marketing team to execute targeted marketing strategies, resulting in a significant 30% increase in conversion rate.
- Analyzed customer feedback to inform product decisions, prioritize feature requests, and develop user stories, resulting in improved product relevance and user satisfaction.
- Supported the CEO in planning the product roadmap and resource tasks using Scrum methodology, which improved project prioritization and execution efficiency.

Client Service Executive Mar 2017 - Mar 2019

Eduspace Technologies Pvt. Ltd. (Proctur) Pune, India

- Utilized user data to address technical issues, resulting in a 40-50% improvement in user satisfaction.
- Addressed an average of 80 customer inquiries monthly, maintaining a 90% satisfaction rate.
- Documented interactions to reduce onboarding time by 30% for new customer service representatives.
- Communicated with customers for product understanding, inquiries, and conflict resolution.